* Tools
    
    * [
        
        Palette Generator Create your palettes in seconds](https://coolors.co/generate)
    * [
        
        Explore Palettes Browse millions of trending color schemes](https://coolors.co/palettes)
    * [
        
        Image Picker Get beautiful palettes from your photos](https://coolors.co/image-picker)
    * [
        
        Contrast Checker Check the contrast between two colors](https://coolors.co/contrast-checker)
    * [
        
        Palette Visualizer
        
        New
        
        Preview your colors on real designs](https://coolors.co/visualizer)
    
    * Apps
        
    * Adobe ExtensionNew
    
* Go Pro

* Sign in
* Sign up
    
    * Profile
    * Sign out

* Other tools

* Jobs

* Apps

* Account
    
* Sign in
* Sign up

* Account
    
* Profile
* Sign out

Privacy Policy
==============

Something we missed? [Email us](https://coolors.co/contact)

Privacy Policy of **Coolors**
=============================

Coolors collects some Personal Data from its Users.

This document contains [a section dedicated to California consumers and their privacy rights](#california_info).

This document contains [a section dedicated to Virginia consumers and their privacy rights](#virginia_info).

This document contains [a section dedicated to Colorado consumers and their privacy rights.](#colorado_info)

This document contains [a section dedicated to Connecticut consumers and their privacy rights.](#connecticut_info)

This document contains [a section dedicated to Utah consumers and their privacy rights.](#utah_info)

This document contains [a section dedicated to Brazilian Users and their privacy rights](#brazil_info).

This document can be printed for reference by using the print command in the settings of any browser.

Owner and Data Controller
-------------------------

**Coolors s.r.l.**  
Piazza Roberto Gaucci, 23  
Colleferro - 00034 - Roma - Italia

**Owner contact email:** [\[email protected\]](https://coolors.co/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Types of Data collected
-----------------------

Among the types of Personal Data that Coolors collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: email address; first name; last name; Trackers; Usage Data; Data communicated while using the service; various types of Data; username; geographic position; profession; picture; password; Universally unique identifier (UUID); device information; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example).

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using Coolors.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by Coolors is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for Coolors to provide its services. In cases where Coolors specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools — by Coolors or by the owners of third-party services used by Coolors serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through Coolors.

Mode and place of processing the Data
-------------------------------------

### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of Coolors (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.  
  
Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

### Retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

The purposes of processing
--------------------------

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Service, comply with its legal obligations, respond to enforcement requests, protect its rights and interests (or those of its Users or third parties), detect any malicious or fraudulent activity, as well as the following: Contacting the User, Traffic optimization and distribution, Advertising, Managing contacts and sending messages, Displaying content from external platforms, Tag Management, Handling payments, Registration and authentication, Platform services and hosting, Collection of privacy-related preferences, Data transfer outside the EU, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Analytics, Social features, Registration and authentication provided directly by Coolors and Interaction with external social networks and platforms.

For specific information about the Personal Data used for each purpose, the User may refer to the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data”.

Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data
-------------------------------------------------------

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Advertising

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes. These communications are displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on Coolors, possibly based on User interests.  
This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
Some of the services listed below may use Trackers to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside Coolors. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.  
Services of this kind usually offer the possibility to opt out of such tracking. In addition to any opt-out feature offered by any of the services below, Users may learn more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section "How to opt-out of interest-based advertising" in this document.

#### Carbon Ads (BuySellAds.com Inc.)

Carbon Ads is an advertising service provided BuySellAds.com Inc.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.buysellads.com/about/privacy?__hstc=194719090.209d2d0efcd7c95a674eaa2f39bb001d.1615826940169.1615826940169.1615826940169.1&__hssc=194719090.1.1615826940169&__hsfp=4053646362).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data until consent is withdrawn.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* a sharing according to the CCPA
* targeted advertising according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### Carbon (Magnite, Inc. (Carbon AI Limited))

Carbon is an advertising service provided by Magnite, Inc. (Carbon AI Limited).

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United Kingdom – [Privacy Policy](https://carbonrmp.com/privacy/) – [Opt out](https://carbonrmp.com/privacy/).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data until consent is withdrawn.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* a sharing according to the CCPA
* targeted advertising according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### BuySellAds (BuySellAds.com Inc.)

BuySellAds is an advertising service provided by BuySellAds.com Inc.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.buysellads.com/about/privacy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data until consent is withdrawn.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* a sharing according to the CCPA
* targeted advertising according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### Hotjar Form Analysis & Conversion Funnels (Hotjar Ltd.)

Hotjar is an analytics service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
Hotjar honors generic Do Not Track headers. This means your browser can tell its script not to collect any of your data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data until consent is withdrawn.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### Direct Advertising (Coolors)

Coolors uses User Data to propose services or products provided by third parties, related or unrelated to the product or service provided by Coolors.

Direct Advertising may involve the use of Trackers to monitor Users’ behavior and serve personalized ads. Users may opt-out of ad personalization by visiting their device settings or following the instructions provided by [YourOnlineChoices](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/) and [AdChoices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Besides applicable device settings, the User may also make use of the rights described under User rights in the relevant section of this privacy policy.

Personal Data processed: device information; Trackers; unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example); Universally unique identifier (UUID); Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Data retention period: Keeping the Data until consent is withdrawn.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers; internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* a sharing according to the CCPA
* targeted advertising according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) with anonymized IP (Google Ireland Limited)

Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) is a web analysis service provided by Google Ireland Limited (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of Coolors, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users' IP addresses within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US.

In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Collection of privacy-related preferences

This type of service allows Coolors to collect and store Users’ preferences related to the collection, use, and processing of their personal information, as requested by the applicable privacy legislation.

#### iubenda Consent Solution (iubenda srl)

The iubenda Consent Solution allows to store and retrieve records of Users’ consent to the processing of Personal Data, and information and preferences expressed in relation to the provided consent.  
In order to do so, it makes use of a Tracker that temporarily stores pending information on the User’s device until it is processed by the API. The Tracker (a browser feature called localStorage) is at that point deleted.

Personal Data processed: Data communicated while using the service; Trackers.

Legal basis for processing: Legal obligation.

Place of processing: Italy – [Privacy Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/94654098).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data as long as required by relevant national law.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### iubenda Cookie Solution (iubenda srl)

The iubenda Cookie Solution allows the Owner to collect and store Users’ preferences related to the processing of personal information, and in particular to the use of Cookies and other Trackers on Coolors.

Personal Data processed: Trackers.

Legal basis for processing: Legal obligation.

Place of processing: Italy – [Privacy Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/36700132).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data as long as required by relevant national law.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Contacting the User

#### Mailing list or newsletter (Coolors)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning Coolors. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to Coolors or after making a purchase.

Personal Data processed: email address; first name; last name.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Data retention period: Keeping the Data until consent is withdrawn.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of Coolors and interact with them.  
This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Google Fonts (Google Ireland Limited)

Google Fonts is a typeface visualization service provided by Google Ireland Limited that allows Coolors to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Handling payments

Unless otherwise specified, Coolors processes any payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means via external payment service providers. In general and unless where otherwise stated, Users are requested to provide their payment details and personal information directly to such payment service providers. Coolors isn't involved in the collection and processing of such information: instead, it will only receive a notification by the relevant payment service provider as to whether payment has been successfully completed.

#### Paddle (Paddle.com Market Limited)

Paddle is a payment management service provided by Paddle.com Market Limited, which allows Users to make online payments. Paddle also allows Coolors to measure the performance of their checkout and subscriptions model, and to re-engage and message Users who have shown signs of abandonment.

Personal Data processed: Trackers.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: United Kingdom – [Privacy Policy](https://paddle.com/privacy-buyers/).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Hosting and backend infrastructure

This type of service has the purpose of hosting Data and files that enable Coolors to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of Coolors.

Some services among those listed below, if any, may work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### Google Cloud Storage (Google Ireland Limited)

Google Cloud Storage is a hosting service provided by Google Ireland Limited.

Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of Coolors.  
The interaction and information obtained through Coolors are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.  
It is recommended to log out from the respective services in order to make sure that the processed data on Coolors isn’t being connected back to the User’s profile.

#### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (X Corp.)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the time necessary to fulfill statistical purposes.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA and VCDPA

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Meta Platforms Ireland Limited)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Meta Platforms Ireland Limited

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the time necessary to fulfill statistical purposes.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### LinkedIn button and social widgets (LinkedIn Corporation)

The LinkedIn button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the LinkedIn social network provided by LinkedIn Corporation.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the time necessary to fulfill statistical purposes.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Managing contacts and sending messages

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

#### Mailjet (SAS Mailjet)

Mailjet is an email address management and message sending service provided by SAS Mailjet.

Personal Data processed: email address; first name; last name.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: France – [Privacy Policy](https://www.mailjet.com/privacy-policy/).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data until consent is withdrawn.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* a sharing according to the CCPA
* targeted advertising according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Platform services and hosting

These services have the purpose of hosting and running key components of Coolors, therefore allowing the provision of Coolors from within a unified platform. Such platforms provide a wide range of tools to the Owner – e.g. analytics, user registration, commenting, database management, e-commerce, payment processing – that imply the collection and handling of Personal Data.  
Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### Google Play Store (Google Ireland Limited)

Coolors is distributed on the Google Play Store, a platform for the distribution of mobile apps, provided by Google Ireland Limited.

By virtue of being distributed via this app store, Google collects usage and diagnostics data and share aggregate information with the Owner. Much of this information is processed on an opt-in basis.

Users may opt-out of this analytics feature directly through their device settings. More information on how to manage analysis settings can be found on [this page](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/6078260).

Personal Data processed: Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### Apple App Store (Apple Inc.)

Coolors is distributed on Apple's App Store, a platform for the distribution of mobile apps, provided by Apple Inc.  
  
By virtue of being distributed via this app store, Apple collects basic analytics and provides reporting features that enables the Owner to view usage analytics data and measure the performance of Coolors. Much of this information is processed on an opt-in basis.  
  
Users may opt-out of this analytics feature directly through their device settings. More information on how to manage analysis settings can be found on this page.  
  
Personal Data processed: Usage Data.  
  
Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy.](https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/)

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* a sharing according to the CCPA
* targeted advertising according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow Coolors to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, Coolors will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.  
Some of the services listed below may also collect Personal Data for targeting and profiling purposes; to find out more, please refer to the description of each service.

#### Google OAuth (Google Ireland Limited)

Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google Ireland Limited and is connected to the Google network.

Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

#### Sign in with Apple (Apple Inc.)

Sign in with Apple is a registration and authentication service provided by Apple Inc. In cases where Users are required to provide their email address, Sign in with Apple may generate a private relay address on behalf of Users that automatically forwards messages to their verified personal email account - therefore shielding their actual email address from the Owner.

Personal Data processed: email address; first name.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Registration and authentication provided directly by Coolors

By registering or authenticating, Users allow Coolors to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. The Personal Data is collected and stored for registration or identification purposes only. The Data collected are only those necessary for the provision of the service requested by the Users.

#### Direct registration (Coolors)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to Coolors.

Personal Data processed: email address; first name; password.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Social features

#### Public profile (Coolors)

Users may have public profiles that other Users can display. In addition to the Personal Data provided, this profile may contain Users' interactions with Coolors.

Personal Data processed: email address; first name; geographic position; last name; picture; profession; username.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers; geolocation data; audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information; employment related information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Tag Management

This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on Coolors in a centralized fashion.  
This results in the Users' Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this Data.

#### Google Tag Manager (Google Ireland Limited)

Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google Ireland Limited.

Personal Data processed: Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

### Traffic optimization and distribution

This type of service allows Coolors to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.  
Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between Coolors and the User's browser.  
Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information of the User are transferred.

#### Cloudflare (Cloudflare Inc.)

Cloudflare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by Cloudflare Inc.  
The way Cloudflare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through Coolors, i.e., communication between Coolors and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data from Coolors to be collected.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Legal basis for processing: Contract.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

Data retention period: Keeping the Data for the duration of the contract (upon termination of the contract, if applicable, as long as required by the applicable law).

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network activity information.

This processing constitutes:

* a sale according to the CCPA, VCDPA, CPA, CTDPA and UCPA
* targeted advertising according to the CPA, CTDPA and UCPA

Information on opting out of interest-based advertising
-------------------------------------------------------

In addition to any opt-out feature provided by any of the services listed in this document, Users may learn more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section of the Cookie Policy.

Further information about the processing of Personal Data
---------------------------------------------------------

### Selling goods and services online

The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.  
The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by Coolors depends on the payment system used.

Cookie Policy
-------------

Coolors uses Trackers. To learn more, Users may consult the [Cookie Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/private/privacy-policy/1384540/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

Further Information for Users
-----------------------------

### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

* Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes.
* provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
* processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
* processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
* processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

### Further information about retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

Therefore:

* Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
* Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to fulfil a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.  
  
Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right of access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

### The rights of Users based on the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following, to the extent permitted by law:

* **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
* **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent.
* **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
* **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
* **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
* **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
* **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance.
* **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis for Data transfers abroad including to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

#### Details about the right to object to processing

**Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.**

**Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time, free of charge and without providing any justification. Where the User objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the Personal Data will no longer be processed for such purposes. To learn whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.**

#### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. Such requests are free of charge and will be answered by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month, providing Users with the information required by law. Any rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing will be communicated by the Owner to each recipient, if any, to whom the Personal Data has been disclosed unless this proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort. At the Users’ request, the Owner will inform them about those recipients.

### Transfer of Personal Data outside of the European Union

#### Data transfer abroad based on standard contractual clauses

If this is the legal basis, the transfer of Personal Data from the EU to third countries is carried out by the Owner according to “standard contractual clauses” provided by the European Commission.  
This means that Data recipients have committed to process Personal Data in compliance with the data protection standards set forth by EU data protection legislation. For further information, Users are requested to contact the Owner through the contact details provided in the present document.

Further information for Users in Brazil
---------------------------------------

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the entity running Coolors and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).  
This section applies to all Users in Brazil (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), according to the "Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados" (the "LGPD"), and for such Users, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.  
This part of the document uses the term “personal information“ as it is defined in the **LGPD**.

### The grounds on which we process your personal information

We can process your personal information solely if we have a legal basis for such processing. Legal bases are as follows:

* your consent to the relevant processing activities;
* compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that lies with us;
* the carrying out of public policies provided in laws or regulations or based on contracts, agreements and similar legal instruments;
* studies conducted by research entities, preferably carried out on anonymized personal information;
* the carrying out of a contract and its preliminary procedures, in cases where you are a party to said contract;
* the exercising of our rights in judicial, administrative or arbitration procedures;
* protection or physical safety of yourself or a third party;
* the protection of health – in procedures carried out by health entities or professionals;
* our legitimate interests, provided that your fundamental rights and liberties do not prevail over such interests; and
* credit protection.

To find out more about the legal bases, you can contact us at any time using the contact details provided in this document.

### Categories of personal information processed

To find out what categories of your personal information are processed, you can read the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.

### Why we process your personal information

To find out why we process your personal information, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

### Your Brazilian privacy rights, how to file a request and our response to your requests

#### Your Brazilian privacy rights

You have the right to:

* obtain confirmation of the existence of processing activities on your personal information;
* access to your personal information;
* have incomplete, inaccurate or outdated personal information rectified;
* obtain the anonymization, blocking or elimination of your unnecessary or excessive personal information, or of information that is not being processed in compliance with the LGPD;
* obtain information on the possibility to provide or deny your consent and the consequences thereof;
* obtain information about the third parties with whom we share your personal information;
* obtain, upon your express request, the portability of your personal information (except for anonymized information) to another service or product provider, provided that our commercial and industrial secrets are safeguarded;
* obtain the deletion of your personal information being processed if the processing was based upon your consent, unless one or more exceptions provided for in art. 16 of the LGPD apply;
* revoke your consent at any time;
* lodge a complaint related to your personal information with the ANPD (the National Data Protection Authority) or with consumer protection bodies;
* oppose a processing activity in cases where the processing is not carried out in compliance with the provisions of the law;
* request clear and adequate information regarding the criteria and procedures used for an automated decision; and
* request the review of decisions made solely on the basis of the automated processing of your personal information, which affect your interests. These include decisions to define your personal, professional, consumer and credit profile, or aspects of your personality.

You will never be discriminated against, or otherwise suffer any sort of detriment, if you exercise your rights.

#### How to file your request

You can file your express request to exercise your rights free from any charge, at any time, by using the contact details provided in this document, or via your legal representative.

#### How and when we will respond to your request

We will strive to promptly respond to your requests.  
In any case, should it be impossible for us to do so, we’ll make sure to communicate to you the factual or legal reasons that prevent us from immediately, or otherwise ever, complying with your requests. In cases where we are not processing your personal information, we will indicate to you the physical or legal person to whom you should address your requests, if we are in the position to do so.

In the event that you file an **access** or personal information **processing confirmation** request, please make sure that you specify whether you’d like your personal information to be delivered in electronic or printed form.  
You will also need to let us know whether you want us to answer your request immediately, in which case we will answer in a simplified fashion, or if you need a complete disclosure instead.  
In the latter case, we’ll respond within 15 days from the time of your request, providing you with all the information on the origin of your personal information, confirmation on whether or not records exist, any criteria used for the processing and the purposes of the processing, while safeguarding our commercial and industrial secrets.

In the event that you file a **rectification, deletion, anonymization or personal information blocking** request, we will make sure to immediately communicate your request to other parties with whom we have shared your personal information in order to enable such third parties to also comply with your request — except in cases where such communication is proven impossible or involves disproportionate effort on our side.

### Transfer of personal information outside of Brazil permitted by the law

We are allowed to transfer your personal information outside of the Brazilian territory in the following cases:

* when the transfer is necessary for international legal cooperation between public intelligence, investigation and prosecution bodies, according to the legal means provided by the international law;
* when the transfer is necessary to protect your life or physical security or those of a third party;
* when the transfer is authorized by the ANPD;
* when the transfer results from a commitment undertaken in an international cooperation agreement;
* when the transfer is necessary for the execution of a public policy or legal attribution of public service;
* when the transfer is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation, the carrying out of a contract or preliminary procedures related to a contract, or the regular exercise of rights in judicial, administrative or arbitration procedures.

Further information for California consumers
--------------------------------------------

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the business running Coolors and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are consumers residing in the state of California, United States of America, according to the "[California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018](https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/codes_displayText.xhtml?division=3.&part=4.&lawCode=CIV&title=1.81.5)" (the "CCPA"), as updated by the "California Privacy Rights Act" (the "CPRA") and subsequent regulations. For such consumers, this section supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the terms “personal information” (and “sensitive personal information”) as defined in the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA).

### Notice at collection

#### Categories of personal information collected, used, sold, or shared

In this section we summarize the categories of personal information that we've collected, used, sold, or shared and the purposes thereof. **You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.**

##### Information we collect: the categories of personal information we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal information about you: identifiers, internet or other electronic network activity information, geolocation data, audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information and employment related information.

We have collected the following categories of sensitive personal information: username and password

We will not collect additional categories of personal information without notifying you.

###### Your right to limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information and how you can exercise it

You have the right to request that we limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information to only that which is necessary to perform the services or provide the goods, as is reasonably expected by an average consumer.

We can also use your sensitive personal information to perform specific purposes set forth by the law (such as, including but not limited to, helping to ensure security and integrity; undertaking activities to verify or maintain the quality or safety of our service) and as authorized by the relevant regulations.

Outside of the aforementioned specific purposes, you have the right to freely request, at any time, that we do not use or disclose your sensitive personal information. This means that whenever you ask us to stop using your sensitive personal information, we will abide by your request and we will instruct our service providers and contractors to do the same.

To fully exercise your right to limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

We use any personal information collected from you in connection with the submission of your request solely for the purposes of complying with the request.

Once you have exercised this right, we are required to wait at least 12 months before asking whether you have changed your mind.

##### What are the purposes for which we use your personal information?

We may use your personal information to allow the operational functioning of Coolors and features thereof (“business purposes”). In such cases, your personal information will be processed in a fashion necessary and proportionate to the business purpose for which it was collected, and strictly within the limits of compatible operational purposes.

We may also use your personal information for other reasons such as for commercial purposes (as indicated within the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document), as well as for complying with the law and defending our rights before the competent authorities where our rights and interests are threatened or we suffer an actual damage.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes originally disclosed, without your consent.

##### How long do we keep your personal information?

Unless stated otherwise inside the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section, we will not retain your personal information for longer than is reasonably necessary for the purpose(s) they have been collected for.

##### How we collect information: what are the sources of the personal information we collect?

We collect the above-mentioned categories of personal information, either directly or indirectly, from you when you use Coolors.

For example, you directly provide your personal information when you submit requests via any forms on Coolors. You also provide personal information indirectly when you navigate Coolors, as personal information about you is automatically observed and collected.

Finally, we may collect your personal information from third parties that work with us in connection with the Service or with the functioning of this Application and features thereof.

##### How we use the information we collect: disclosing of your personal information with third parties for a business purpose

For our purposes, the word “third party” means a person who is not any of the following: a service provider or a contractor, as defined by the CCPA.

We disclose your personal information with the third parties **listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.** These third parties are grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

##### Sale or sharing of your personal information

For our purposes, the word “sale” means any “selling, renting, releasing, disclosing, disseminating, making available, transferring or otherwise communicating orally, in writing, or by electronic means, a consumer's personal information by the business to **a third party, for monetary or other valuable consideration**”, as defined by the CCPA.

This means that, for example, a sale can happen whenever an application runs ads, or makes statistical analyses on the traffic or views, or simply because it uses tools such as social network plugins and the like.

For our purposes, the word “sharing” means any “sharing, renting, releasing, disclosing, disseminating, making available, transferring, or otherwise communicating orally, in writing, or by electronic or other means, a consumer's personal information by the business to a third party for cross-context behavioral advertising, whether or not for monetary or other valuable consideration, including transactions between a business and a third party for cross-context behavioral advertising for the benefit of a business in which no money is exchanged”, as defined by the CCPA.  
Please note that the exchange of personal information with a service provider pursuant to a written contract that meets the requirements set by the CCPA, does not constitute a sale or sharing of your personal information.

###### Your right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your personal information and how you can exercise it

We sell or share your personal information with the third parties **listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.** These third parties are grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.  
  
You have the right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your personal information. This means that whenever you request us to stop selling or sharing your personal information, we will abide by your request.  
Such requests can be made freely, at any time, without submitting any verifiable request.  
To fully exercise your right to opt out, you can contact us at any time using the contact details provided in this document.  
For a simplified opt-out method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

If you want to submit requests to opt out of the sale or sharing of personal information via a user-enabled global privacy control, like the Global Privacy Control (“[GPC](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/)”), you are free to do so and we will abide by such request in a frictionless manner (as defined in the CPRA regulations). The GPC consists of a setting or extension in the browser or mobile device and acts as a mechanism that websites can use to indicate they support the GPC signal. If you want to use GPC, you can download and enable it via a [participating browser](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/#download) or browser extension. More information about downloading GPC is available [here](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/).

We use any personal information collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purposes of complying with the opt-out request.

Once you have opted out, we are required to wait at least 12 months before asking whether you have changed your mind.

##### What are the purposes for which we use your personal information?

We may use your personal information to allow the operational functioning of Coolors and features thereof (“business purposes”). In such cases, your personal information will be processed in a fashion necessary and proportionate to the business purpose for which it was collected, and strictly within the limits of compatible operational purposes.

We may also use your personal information for other reasons such as for commercial purposes (as indicated within the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document), as well as for complying with the law and defending our rights before the competent authorities where our rights and interests are threatened or we suffer an actual damage.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes originally disclosed, without your consent.

##### How long do we keep your personal information?

Unless stated otherwise inside the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section, we will not retain your personal information for longer than is reasonably necessary for the purpose(s) they have been collected for.

### Your privacy rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act and how to exercise them

#### The right to access personal information: the right to know and to portability

You have the right to request that we disclose to you:

* the categories of personal information that we collect about you;
* the sources from which the personal information is collected;
* the purposes for which we use your information;
* to whom we disclose such information;
* the specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you.

You also have **the right to know what personal information is sold or shared and to whom.** In particular, you have the right to request two separate lists from us where we disclose:

* the categories of personal information that we sold or shared about you and the categories of third parties to whom the personal information was sold or shared;
* the categories of personal information that we disclosed about you for a business purpose and the categories of persons to whom it was disclosed for a business purpose.

The disclosure described above will be limited to the personal information collected or used over the past 12 months.

If we deliver our response electronically, the information enclosed will be "portable", i.e. delivered in an easily usable format to enable you to transmit the information to another entity without hindrance — provided that this is technically feasible.

#### The right to request the deletion of your personal information

You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information, subject to exceptions set forth by the law (such as, including but not limited to, where the information is used to identify and repair errors on Coolors, to detect security incidents and protect against fraudulent or illegal activities, to exercise certain rights etc.).

If no legal exception applies, as a result of exercising your right, we will delete your personal information and notify any of our service providers and all third parties to whom we have sold or shared the personal information to do so — provided that this is technically feasible and doesn’t involve disproportionate effort.

#### The right to correct inaccurate personal information

You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal information we maintain about you, taking into account the nature of the personal information and the purposes of the processing of the personal information.

#### The right to opt out of sale or sharing of personal information and to limit the use of your sensitive personal information

You have the right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your personal information. You also have the right to request that we limit our use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information.

#### The right of no retaliation following opt-out or exercise of other rights (the right to non-discrimination)

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. This means that we will not discriminate against you, including, but not limited to, by denying goods or services, charging you a different price, or providing a different level or quality of goods or services just because you exercised your consumer privacy rights.

However, if you refuse to provide your personal information to us or ask us to delete or stop selling your personal information, and that personal information or sale is necessary for us to provide you with goods or services, we may not be able to complete that transaction.

To the extent permitted by the law, we may offer you promotions, discounts, and other deals in exchange for collecting, keeping, or selling your personal information, provided that the financial incentive offered is reasonably related to the value of your personal information.

#### How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your verifiable request to us by contacting us via the details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, it’s necessary that we know who you are. Therefore, you can only exercise the above rights by making a verifiable request which must:

* provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative;
* describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity and therefore confirm the personal information in our possession actually relates to you.

Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will use any personal information collected from you in connection with the verification of your request solely for the purposes of verification and shall not further disclose the personal information, retain it longer than necessary for purposes of verification, or use it for unrelated purposes.

If you cannot personally submit a verifiable request, you can authorize a person registered with the California Secretary of State to act on your behalf.

If you are an adult, you can make a verifiable request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

You can submit a maximum number of 2 requests over a period of 12 months.

#### How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will confirm receipt of your verifiable request within 10 days and provide information about how we will process your request.

We will respond to your request within 45 days of its receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Our disclosure(s) will cover the preceding 12-month period. Only with regard to personal information collected on or after January 1, 2022, you have the right to request that we disclose information beyond the 12-month period, and we will provide them to you unless doing so proves impossible or would involve a disproportionate effort.

Should we deny your request, we will explain you the reasons behind our denial.

We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable request unless such request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. In such cases, we may charge a reasonable fee, or refuse to act on the request. In either case, we will communicate our choices and explain the reasons behind it.

Further information for Virginia consumers
------------------------------------------

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the controller running this Application and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are consumers residing in the Commonwealth of Virginia, according to the [“Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act"](https://law.lis.virginia.gov/vacode/title59.1/chapter53/) (the "VCDPA"), and, for such consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the VCDPA.

### Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes thereof. **You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Persona Data” within this document**.

#### Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, internet information, geolocation data, sensorial information and employment related information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

#### Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes originally disclosed, without your consent.  
You can freely give, deny, or withdraw such consent at any time using the contact details provided in this document.

#### How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties **listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document**. These third parties are grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.  
For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a natural or legal person, public authority, agency, or body other than the consumer, controller, processor, or an affiliate of the processor or the controller" as defined by the VCDPA.

#### Sale of your personal data

For our purposes, the word “sale” means any “exchange of personal data for monetary consideration by us to a third party“ as defined by the VCDPA.  
Please note that according to the VCDPA, the disclosure of personal data to a processor that processes personal data on behalf of a controller does not constitute a sale. In addition, other specific exceptions set forth in the VCDPA may apply, such as, but not limited to, the disclosure of personal data to a third party for the provision of a product or service requested by you.  
As specified in the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section of this document, our use of your personal information may be considered a sale under VCDPA.

##### Your right to opt out of the sale of your personal data and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal data. This means that whenever you request us to stop selling your data, we will abide by your request. To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time using the contact details provided in this document.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purpose of complying with the request.

#### Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

For our purposes, the word "targeted advertising" means "displaying advertisements to you where the advertisement is selected based on personal data obtained from your activities over time and across nonaffiliated websites or online applications to predict your preferences or interests" as defined by the VCDPA.  
  
Please note that according to the VCDPA, targeted advertising does not include: “advertisements based on activities within a controller's own websites or online applications; advertisements based on the context of a consumer's current search query, visit to a website or online application; advertisements directed to a consumer in response to the consumer's request for information or feedback; or processing personal data solely for measuring or reporting advertising performance, reach, or frequency”.

To find out more details on the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising purposes, you can read the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.

##### Your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising. This means that whenever you ask us to stop processing your data for targeted advertising, we will abide by your request. To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purposes of complying with the opt-out request.

### Your privacy rights under the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act and how to exercise them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do the following:

* **access personal data: the right to know.** You have the right to request that we confirm whether or not we are processing your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.
* **correct inaccurate personal data.** You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal data we maintain about you, taking into account the nature of the personal data and the purposes of the processing of the personal data.
* **request the deletion of your personal data.** You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal data.
* **obtain a copy of your personal data.** We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable format that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity — provided that this is technically feasible.
* **opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising**, the **sale of personal data**, or **profiling** in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you.
* **non-discrimination.** We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the VCDPA. This means that we will not, among other things, deny goods or services, charge you a different price, or provide a different level or quality of goods or services just because you exercised your consumer privacy rights. However, if you refuse to provide your personal data to us or ask us to delete or stop selling your personal data, and that personal data or sale is necessary for us to provide you with goods or services, we may not be able to complete that transaction. To the extent permitted by the law, we may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or services to you, including offering goods or services for no fee, if you have exercised your right to opt out, or our offer is related to your voluntary participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card program.

#### How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases, we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you and your request.

Making a consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. However, we may require you to use your existing account. We will use any personal data collected from you in connection with your request solely for the purposes of authentication, without further disclosing the personal data, retaining it longer than necessary for purposes of authentication, or using it for unrelated purposes.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

#### How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request. It is your right to appeal such decision by submitting a request to us via the details provided in this document. Within 60 days of receipt of the appeal, we will inform you in writing of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal, including a written explanation of the reasons for the decisions. If the appeal is denied you may [contact the Attorney General to submit a complaint](https://www.oag.state.va.us/consumer-protection/index.php/file-a-complaint).

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to two requests per year. If your request is manifestly unfounded, excessive or repetitive, we may charge a reasonable fee or refuse to act on the request. In either case, we will communicate our choices and explain the reasons behind them.

Further information for Colorado consumers
------------------------------------------

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the controller running Coolors and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are consumers residing in the State of Colorado, according to the “Colorado Privacy Act" (the "CPA"), and, for such consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the CPA.

### Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes thereof. **You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Persona Data” within this document**.

#### Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, internet information, geolocation data, sensorial information and employment related information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

#### Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes originally disclosed, without your consent.  
You can freely give, deny, or withdraw such consent at any time using the contact details provided in this document.

#### How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties **listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document**. These third parties are grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a person, public authority, agency, or body other than a consumer, controller, processor, or affiliate of the processor or the controller." as defined by the CPA.

#### Sale of your personal data

As specified in the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section of this document, our use of your personal data may be considered a sale under the CPA.

For our purposes, the word "sale", "sell", or "sold" means "the exchange of personal data for monetary or other valuable consideration by a controller to a third party" as defined by the CPA.

Please note that according to the CPA, the disclosure of personal data to a processor that processes personal data on behalf of a controller does not constitute a sale. In addition, other specific exceptions set forth in the CPA may apply, such as, but not limited to, the disclosure of personal data to a third party for the provision of a product or service requested by you.

##### Your right to opt out of the sale of your personal data and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal data. This means that whenever you request us to stop selling your data, we will abide by your request.

To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified opt-out method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purpose of complying with the request.

#### Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

As specified in the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section of this document, we may use your personal data for targeted advertising purposes.

For our purposes, the word "targeted advertising" means "displaying to a consumer an advertisement that is selected based on personal data obtained or inferred over time from the consumer's activities across nonaffiliated websites, applications, or online services to predict consumer preferences or interests" as defined by CPA.  
  
Please note that according to the CPA, targeted advertising does not include: “advertisements directed to a consumer in response to the consumer's request for information or feedback; advertisements based on activities within a controller's own websites or online applications or any affiliated website or online application; advertisements based on the context of a consumer's current search query, visit to an internet web site or online application; or processing personal data solely to measure or report advertising frequency, performance or reach”.

##### Your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising. This means that whenever you ask us to stop processing your data for targeted advertising, we will abide by your request.

To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified opt-out method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purposes of complying with the opt-out request.

##### Universal opt-out mechanism: Global privacy control

If you want to submit requests to opt-out of the sale of personal data or the targeted advertising via a user-enabled global privacy control, like the Global Privacy Control (“[GPC](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/)”), you are free to do so and we will abide by such request. The GPC consists of a setting or extension in the browser or mobile device and acts as a mechanism that websites can use to indicate they support the GPC signal. If you want to use GPC, you can download and enable it via a participating browser or browser extension. More information about downloading GPC is available [here](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/).

### Your privacy rights under the Colorado Privacy Act and how to exercise them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do the following:

* opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of personal data, or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you.
* access personal data. You have the right to request that we confirm whether or not we are processing your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.
* correct inaccurate personal data. You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal data we maintain about you, taking into account the nature of the personal data and the purposes of the processing of the personal data.
* request the deletion of your personal data. You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal data.
* obtain a copy of your personal data. We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable format that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity – provided that this is technically feasible.

In any case, we will not increase the cost of, or decrease the availability of, a product or service, based solely on the exercise of any of your rights and unrelated to the feasibility or the value of a service. However, to the extent permitted by the law, we may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or services to you, including offering goods or services for no fee, if our offer is related to your voluntary participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card program.

#### How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are and which right you wish to exercise.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases, we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you and your request.

Making a consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. However, we may require you to use your existing account. We will use any personal data collected from you in connection with your request solely for the purposes of authentication, without further disclosing the personal data, retaining it longer than necessary for purposes of authentication, or using it for unrelated purposes.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

#### How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request. It is your right to appeal such decision by submitting a request to us via the details provided in this document. Within 45 days of receipt of the appeal, we will inform you in writing of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal, including a written explanation of the reasons for the decisions. If the appeal is denied you may contact the Attorney General to submit a complaint.

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to two requests per year.

Further information for Connecticut consumers
---------------------------------------------

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the controller running Coolors and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).

This section applies o all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are consumers residing in the State of Connecticut, according to “An Act Concerning Personal Data Privacy and Online Monitoring " (also known as "The Connecticut Data Privacy Act" or the “CTDPA"), and, for such consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the CTDPA.

### Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes thereof. **You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Persona Data” within this document**.

#### Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, internet information, geolocation data, sensorial information and employment related information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

#### Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes originally disclosed, without your consent.  
You can freely give, deny, or withdraw such consent at any time using the contact details provided in this document.

#### How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties **listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document**. These third parties are grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a person, public authority, agency, or body other than a consumer, controller, processor, or affiliate of the processor or the controller." as defined by the CTDPA.

#### Sale of your personal data

As specified in the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section of this document, our use of your personal data may be considered a sale under the CTDPA.

For our purposes, the word "sale", "sell", or "sold" means "the exchange of personal data for monetary or other valuable consideration by a controller to a third party" as defined by the CTDPA.

Please note that according to the CTDPA, the disclosure of personal data to a processor that processes personal data on behalf of a controller does not constitute a sale. In addition, other specific exceptions set forth in the CTDPA may apply, such as, but not limited to, the disclosure of personal data to a third party for the provision of a product or service requested by you.

##### Your right to opt out of the sale of your personal data and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal data. This means that whenever you request us to stop selling your data, we will abide by your request.

To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified opt-out method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purpose of complying with the request.

#### Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

As specified in the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section of this document, we may use your personal data for targeted advertising purposes.

For our purposes, the word "targeted advertising" means "displaying to a consumer an advertisement that is selected based on personal data obtained or inferred over time from the consumer's activities across non affiliated websites, applications, or online services to predict consumer preferences or interests" as defined by CTDPA.  
  
Please note that according to the CTDPA, targeted advertising does not include: “advertisements based on activities within a controller's own web sites or online applications; advertisements based on the context of a consumer's current search query, visit to an internet web site or online application; advertisements directed to a consumer in response to the consumer's request for information or feedback; or processing personal data solely to measure or report advertising frequency, performance or reach”.

##### Your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising. This means that whenever you ask us to stop processing your data for targeted advertising, we will abide by your request.

To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified opt-out method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purposes of complying with the opt-out request.

##### Universal opt-out mechanism: Global privacy control

If you want to submit requests to opt-out of the sale of personal data or the targeted advertising via a user-enabled global privacy control, like the Global Privacy Control (“[GPC](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/)”), you are free to do so and we will abide by such request. The GPC consists of a setting or extension in the browser or mobile device and acts as a mechanism that websites can use to indicate they support the GPC signal. If you want to use GPC, you can download and enable it via a participating browser or browser extension. More information about downloading GPC is available [here](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/).

### Your privacy rights under the Connecticut Data Privacy Act and how to exercise them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do the following:

* access personal data. You have the right to request that we confirm whether or not we are processing your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.
* correct inaccurate personal data. You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal data we maintain about you, taking into account the nature of the personal data and the purposes of the processing of the personal data.
* request the deletion of your personal data. You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal data.
* obtain a copy of your personal data. We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable format that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity – provided that this is technically feasible.
* opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of personal data, or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you.

In any case, we will not increase the cost of, or decrease the availability of, a product or service, based solely on the exercise of any of your rights and unrelated to the feasibility or the value of a service. However, to the extent permitted by the law, we may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or services to you, including offering goods or services for no fee, if our offer is related to your voluntary participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card program.

#### How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are and which right you wish to exercise.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases, we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you and your request.

Making a consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. However, we may require you to use your existing account. We will use any personal data collected from you in connection with your request solely for the purposes of authentication, without further disclosing the personal data, retaining it longer than necessary for purposes of authentication, or using it for unrelated purposes.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

#### How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request. It is your right to appeal such decision by submitting a request to us via the details provided in this document. Within 45 days of receipt of the appeal, we will inform you in writing of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal, including a written explanation of the reasons for the decisions. If the appeal is denied, you may [contact the Attorney General to submit a complaint](https://portal.ct.gov/AG/Common/Complaint-Form-Landing-page).

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to one request per year.

Further information for Utah consumers
--------------------------------------

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the controller running Coolors and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are consumers residing in the State of Utah, according to the “Consumer Privacy Act" (the “UCPA"), and, for such consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the UCPA.

### Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes thereof. **You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Persona Data” within this document**.

#### Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, internet information, geolocation data, sensorial information and employment related information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

#### Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

#### How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties **listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document**. These third parties are grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a person other than: the consumer, controller, or processor; or an affiliate or contractor of the controller or the processor" as defined by the UCPA.

#### Sale of your personal data

As specified in the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section of this document, our use of your personal data may be considered a sale under the UCPA.

For our purposes, the word "sale", "sell", or "sold" means "the exchange of personal data for monetary or other valuable consideration by a controller to a third party" as defined by the UCPA.

Please note that according to the UCPA, the disclosure of personal data to a processor that processes personal data on behalf of a controller does not constitute a sale. In addition, other specific exceptions set forth in the UCPA may apply, such as, but not limited to, the disclosure of personal data to a third party for the provision of a product or service requested by you.

##### Your right to opt out of the sale of your personal data and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal data. This means that whenever you request us to stop selling your data, we will abide by your request.

To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified opt-out method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purpose of complying with the request.

#### Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

As specified in the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section of this document, we may use your personal data for targeted advertising purposes.

For our purposes, the word "targeted advertising" means "displaying to a consumer an advertisement that is selected based on personal data obtained or inferred over time from the consumer's activities across nonaffiliated websites, applications, or online services to predict consumer preferences or interests" as defined by UCPA.  
  
Please note that according to the UCPA, targeted advertising does not include: “advertisements based on activities within a controller's own websites or online applications or any affiliated website or online application; advertisements based on the context of a consumer's current search query, visit to an web site or online application; advertisements directed to a consumer in response to the consumer's request for information, product, a service or feedback; or processing personal data solely to measure or report advertising performance, reach or frequency.”

##### Your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising and how you can exercise it

You have the right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted advertising. This means that whenever you ask us to stop processing your data for targeted advertising, we will abide by your request.

To fully exercise your right to opt out you can contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified opt-out method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Coolors.

We use any personal data collected from you in connection with the submission of your opt-out request solely for the purposes of complying with the opt-out request.

### Your privacy rights under the Utah Consumer Privacy Act and how to exercise them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do the following:

* access personal data. You have the right to request that we confirm whether or not we are processing your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.
* request the deletion of your personal data. You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal data.
* obtain a copy of your personal data. We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable format that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity – provided that this is technically feasible.
* opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising or the sale of personal data.

In any case, we will not increase the cost of, or decrease the availability of, a product or service, based solely on the exercise of any of your rights and unrelated to the feasibility or the value of a service. However, to the extent permitted by the law, we may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or services to you, including offering goods or services for no fee, if our offer is related to your voluntary participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card program.

#### How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are and which right you wish to exercise.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases, we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you and your request. We may retain your email address to respond to your request.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

#### How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request.

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to one request per year.

Additional information about Data collection and processing
-----------------------------------------------------------

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of Coolors or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, Coolors may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, Coolors and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with Coolors (System logs) or use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by notifying its Users on this page and possibly within Coolors and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible - sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.  
  
Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

Further information for Users in Brazil
---------------------------------------

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the privacy policy and is provided by the entity running Coolors and, if the case may be, its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).  
This section applies to all Users in Brazil (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), according to the "Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados" (the "LGPD"), and for such Users, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.  
This part of the document uses the term “personal information“ as it is defined in the **LGPD**.

### The grounds on which we process your personal information

We can process your personal information solely if we have a legal basis for such processing. Legal bases are as follows:

* your consent to the relevant processing activities;
* compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that lies with us;
* the carrying out of public policies provided in laws or regulations or based on contracts, agreements and similar legal instruments;
* studies conducted by research entities, preferably carried out on anonymized personal information;
* the carrying out of a contract and its preliminary procedures, in cases where you are a party to said contract;
* the exercising of our rights in judicial, administrative or arbitration procedures;
* protection or physical safety of yourself or a third party;
* the protection of health – in procedures carried out by health entities or professionals;
* our legitimate interests, provided that your fundamental rights and liberties do not prevail over such interests; and
* credit protection.

To find out more about the legal bases, you can contact us at any time using the contact details provided in this document.

### Categories of personal information processed

To find out what categories of your personal information are processed, you can read the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.

### Why we process your personal information

To find out why we process your personal information, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

### Your Brazilian privacy rights, how to file a request and our response to your requests

#### Your Brazilian privacy rights

You have the right to:

* obtain confirmation of the existence of processing activities on your personal information;
* access to your personal information;
* have incomplete, inaccurate or outdated personal information rectified;
* obtain the anonymization, blocking or elimination of your unnecessary or excessive personal information, or of information that is not being processed in compliance with the LGPD;
* obtain information on the possibility to provide or deny your consent and the consequences thereof;
* obtain information about the third parties with whom we share your personal information;
* obtain, upon your express request, the portability of your personal information (except for anonymized information) to another service or product provider, provided that our commercial and industrial secrets are safeguarded;
* obtain the deletion of your personal information being processed if the processing was based upon your consent, unless one or more exceptions provided for in art. 16 of the LGPD apply;
* revoke your consent at any time;
* lodge a complaint related to your personal information with the ANPD (the National Data Protection Authority) or with consumer protection bodies;
* oppose a processing activity in cases where the processing is not carried out in compliance with the provisions of the law;
* request clear and adequate information regarding the criteria and procedures used for an automated decision; and
* request the review of decisions made solely on the basis of the automated processing of your personal information, which affect your interests. These include decisions to define your personal, professional, consumer and credit profile, or aspects of your personality.

You will never be discriminated against, or otherwise suffer any sort of detriment, if you exercise your rights.

#### How to file your request

You can file your express request to exercise your rights free from any charge, at any time, by using the contact details provided in this document, or via your legal representative.

#### How and when we will respond to your request

We will strive to promptly respond to your requests.  
In any case, should it be impossible for us to do so, we’ll make sure to communicate to you the factual or legal reasons that prevent us from immediately, or otherwise ever, complying with your requests. In cases where we are not processing your personal information, we will indicate to you the physical or legal person to whom you should address your requests, if we are in the position to do so.

In the event that you file an **access** or personal information **processing confirmation** request, please make sure that you specify whether you’d like your personal information to be delivered in electronic or printed form.  
You will also need to let us know whether you want us to answer your request immediately, in which case we will answer in a simplified fashion, or if you need a complete disclosure instead.  
In the latter case, we’ll respond within 15 days from the time of your request, providing you with all the information on the origin of your personal information, confirmation on whether or not records exist, any criteria used for the processing and the purposes of the processing, while safeguarding our commercial and industrial secrets.

In the event that you file a **rectification, deletion, anonymization or personal information blocking** request, we will make sure to immediately communicate your request to other parties with whom we have shared your personal information in order to enable such third parties to also comply with your request — except in cases where such communication is proven impossible or involves disproportionate effort on our side.

### Transfer of personal information outside of Brazil permitted by the law

We are allowed to transfer your personal information outside of the Brazilian territory in the following cases:

* when the transfer is necessary for international legal cooperation between public intelligence, investigation and prosecution bodies, according to the legal means provided by the international law;
* when the transfer is necessary to protect your life or physical security or those of a third party;
* when the transfer is authorized by the ANPD;
* when the transfer results from a commitment undertaken in an international cooperation agreement;
* when the transfer is necessary for the execution of a public policy or legal attribution of public service;
* when the transfer is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation, the carrying out of a contract or preliminary procedures related to a contract, or the regular exercise of rights in judicial, administrative or arbitration procedures.

### Definitions and legal references

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through Coolors (or third-party services employed in Coolors), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use Coolors, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using Coolors who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Processor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of Coolors. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of Coolors.

#### Coolors (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

The service provided by Coolors as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU)

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

#### Cookie

Cookies are Trackers consisting of small sets of data stored in the User's browser.

#### Tracker

Tracker indicates any technology - e.g Cookies, unique identifiers, web beacons, embedded scripts, e-tags and fingerprinting - that enables the tracking of Users, for example by accessing or storing information on the User’s device.

#### Legal information

This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations.

This privacy policy relates solely to Coolors, if not stated otherwise within this document.

Latest update: March 07, 2024

* Tools

* More

* Jobs
* Apps
* Adobe ExtensionNew

* Company
* Manage cookies

© Coolors by [Fabrizio Bianchi](http://fabrizio.io/). From a creative to all the others.

Sign in
-------

Sign in with your email here.

Sign in

By continuing, you agree to our [Terms of Service](https://coolors.co/terms-of-service).  
Read our [Privacy Policy](https://coolors.co/privacy-policy).

Forgot password? Reset  
Don't have an account? Sign up

Sign up
-------

Create a free account with your email.

Create your free account

By continuing, you agree to our [Terms of Service](https://coolors.co/terms-of-service).  
Read our [Privacy Policy](https://coolors.co/privacy-policy).

Already have an account? Sign in

You're all set!
---------------

We're thrilled to have you on board!  
Enjoy Coolors!

Okay

Reset password

Enter your email address below and choose a new password.

Email / Username

This field is required

This email is not registered

Choose a new password

This field is required

Min 8 characters

Send reset link

Back to Sign in

Color code

Color code

This field is required

The code is not valid.

This code has been already used.

This code has expired.

Too many attempts. Try again in 1 minute.

Email not received? Send again  
Do you need help? [Contact us](https://coolors.co/contact)

Export Palette

URL Share PDF Image CSS ASE SVG Code Embed Facebook Twitter Pinterest

Export palette as PDF

Title 

Description

Colors Label

Color Spaces

Pages

 Use my custom [logo](https://coolors.co/account/settings)

Export

Export as PDF

Title 

Description

 Use my custom [logo](https://coolors.co/account/settings)

Export

Export palette as image

Title 

Color Space

Colors Label

 Use my custom [logo](https://coolors.co/account/settings)

Export

Name 

Description

Tags

Select projects

 Add

Select collections

 Add

Label 

Color

Add context to your palette by pairing it with an image.

Use picker image

Save

Name

This field is required

 Private

Save

Name

This field is required

 Private

Save

Name 

Color

This field is required

Color already saved

Save

Name 

Description

Tags

Preview

Colors

Select projects

 Add

Select collections

 Add

Save

Select image

Browse or drop image

Wrong file type or size (max 10 MB).

Image URL

This field is required

OK

No photos found.

Not available. Please try later.

Allow access to your camera...

Camera not available.

Not supported by your device.

Camera access denied.

Retake

Use this photo

Take

Image picker

Next

Collage maker

Export

Share palette

Facebook Twitter Pinterest

What's new

Howdy!

Thank you so much for getting here! I’m Fabrizio, creator and maintainer of Coolors. I’d really love to get in touch with you to hear your feedback or just say hello! 😃

Reach me on

New terms available

We updated our [Terms](https://coolors.co/terms-of-service) and [Privacy](https://coolors.co/privacy-policy).  
Please read them and accept to continue.

I accept

Download Copy

Palette Luminance

Palette Gradient

Check Palette Contrast

Pro Feature

Go Pro to unlock this feature and many others.

Learn more View demo

No color pairs have enough contrast.

ValidAll

Export color as image

Title 

Space

Library

 Use my custom [logo](https://coolors.co/account/settings)

Export

Select project

Projects

New project 

OK

Select collection

Collections

New collection 

OK

Share

link\_sharer\_description

Private link to share 

Palette details

Projects

Collections

Tags

Keywords

Created on

modal\_pro\_subtitle

👋 Hello, I'm Fabrizio, the guy behind Coolors. Today I introduce Coolors Pro, a subscription plan to premium features, that I believe represents a fundamental step forward for the future of Coolors' development.

So what happens? You can still use nearly every features for free, with mainly these limitations on the account:

* You can save up to **10 palettes**
* You can have only **1 project** and **1 collection**
* You can save up to **5 colors** to favorites

* **Remove ads** and popups to enter the heaven of colors
* **Generate palettes** with more than 5 colors automatically or with color theory rules
* Save **unlimited palettes**, colors and gradients, and organize them in projects and collections
* Explore more than **10 million color schemes** perfect for any project
* **Pro Profile**, a new beautiful page to present yourself and showcase your palettes, projects and collections
* Get **advanced PDF export** options like shades, hues, color blindness, etc.
* Unlock additional tools like the new **Palette Visualizer** to check your colors on real designs
* **Support me** as an indie [developer](https://fabrizio.io/)

**Cancel your subscription anytime.** We'll send you reminders 3 days before renewals.

Used by 5+ million users

And top companies

Redeem your coupon

Coupon code

This field is required

This coupon is not valid.

This coupon has expired.

This coupon has been already used.

Apply

[Contact us](https://coolors.co/contact) if you need support with your coupon.

Update payment method

Provide your card details (protected by [Stripe](https://stripe.com/))

Confirm

Update payment method

Update payment method

Change Plan

Hello!
------

Use your email or another service to continue with Coolors.

Continue with Google Continue with Apple Continue with email

By continuing, you agree to our [Terms of Service](https://coolors.co/terms-of-service).  
Read our [Privacy Policy](https://coolors.co/privacy-policy).

Share a palette quickly with your clients or collegues, including title and descriptions.

Name 

Description

Label

Color

Get link

Become an Affiliate!

If you have a blog, website, email list or social media accounts then you can join the Affiliate Program and earn a 20% commission on every purchase.

Get your link

Variants

1 2 3 4

Title

This field is required

Description

This field is required

Creative fields

This field is required

Tools

Tags

 Private

Request an invitation

We can't wait to see what you are working on but, to prevent abuse and scale gradually, you you can start uploading your designs only upon invitation.

Make sure your profile is well sorted out before sending your request!

Send a request

Your already sent your request.

Name 

Description

Tags

Select projects

 Add

Select collections

 Add

Save

Palette Variations

Show HEX 

Pro Feature

Go Pro to unlock this feature and many others.

Learn more View demo

### Coolors Adobe Extension

Download and install the extension for Illustrator, InDesign and Photoshop (up to version 20). Photoshop 21+ and Adobe XD will be supported soon.

Adobe Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop (20)

Download (1.1.0)

Adobe Photoshop 21+, Adobe XD

Coming soon

Parse Palette

Coolors URL / String / Array

This field is required

No colors found

OK

Prev

Next

Cancel subscription

Oh no! It breaks my 💙  
to see you leave!

Before you cancel your subscription, please share with me what made you cancel today. Your honest feedback will help me improve a lot! Thanks.

Never mind, I'll stay! Continue

Name 

Description

Tags

Select projects

 Add

Select collections

 Add

Save

Allow the ads
-------------

Hey, I'm Fabrizio, the guy behind this website. Please help me to keep most of the site free by allowing ads or consider subscribing to enjoy even more features.  
  
Your support truly matters.

I disabled the ad blocker I want to subscribe for $3/mo

I don't care, close popup
